narro.co 2019-09-04

# Privacy Policy for Narro

This policy applies to all information collected or submitted on Narro's website and our apps for iPhone, Android, Chrome, and any other devices and platforms.

## Information We Collect

When creating an account, you will be asked to enter an email address and a password.

When adding content to your Narro feed, like articles, text, ebooks, or any other submissions, we retain that data, along with the generated audio of that content.

If you enable push notifications on a device, we need to store the token your device gives us to send them. We only ever use push notifications to initiate background downloads and notify you of newly generated audio. We never use push notifications for marketing.

We use cookies on the site and similar tokens in any apps to keep you logged in.

Like most websites and apps, we also store information through the use of software that may be transparent to users. For example, we may log your IP address and general information about your browser or device using the third-party Google Analytics.

When upgrading your account to a Pro level, we use a third-party (Stripe) to collect and charge your credit card. Narro does not store this information. We only store the resulting charges and dates.

We do not collect any "Special Categories of Personal Data" about you.

## Information Usage

We use the information we collect to operate and improve our website, apps, and customer support.

We do not send promotional emails. Your email address is only used for:

  * Signing in.
  * Resetting your password if you forget it.
  * Responding to any feedback or support emails you send us.
  * Notifying you of important account-related matters, such as security or billing problems.

We do not share your personal information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to accomplish Narro's functionality.

We may share anonymous, aggregate statistics with outside parties, such as how many people listen to a particular article or podcast via Narro.

We may disclose your information in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal requirements; to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud or abuse, violations of our policies; or to protect our rights and property.

In the future, we may sell to, buy, merge with, or partner with other businesses. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets.

## Security and Storage of Information

We implement a variety of security measures to help keep your information secure.

For instance, passwords are not stored: they are [hashed](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptographic_hash_function) using advanced, well-researched methods. (At the time of writing, [bcrypt](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt) is used, but that may be upgraded to a more advanced algorithm in the future such as [scrypt](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrypt) without notice.)

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or it is reasonably needed for the purposes set out in "Information Usage" unless you request that we remove your personal data as described in "Accessing Your Information". 

Narro is based in the United States, and maintains all services and storage in the United States. Although we welcome users from all over the world, by accessing the Services and providing us with your personal data, you consent to and authorize the export of personal data to the United States and its storage and use as specified in this Privacy Policy. Note the laws of the United States might not be as comprehensive or protective as laws in the country where you live.

## Accessing Your Information

You may access or change your information or delete your account at any time by logging into the website or any future apps. Additionally, you may email the address at the bottom of this page to request your data in a machine readable format. We will respond to all legitimate requests within one month. If you request that we remove your account or personal information, we will convey that request to any third-party with whom we have shared your data.

Your submitted content and generated audio are always readily downloadable via your Narro podcast URL.

## Third-party Links and Content

Narro displays links and content from third-party website feeds and sites, and downloads html content directly from each site's third-party servers. These have their own independent privacy policies, and we have no responsibility or liability for their content or activities.

## California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We comply with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

## Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

## General Data Protection Regulation Compliance

Under the GDPR, you are entitled to certain rights, including: (i) the right to withdraw consent to processing where consent is the basis of processing; (ii) the right to access your personal information and certain other supplementary information, under certain conditions; (iii) the right to object to unlawful data processing, under certain conditions; (iv) the right to erasure of personal information about you, under certain conditions; (v) the right to demand that we restrict processing of your personal information, under certain conditions, if you believe we have exceeded the legitimate basis for processing, processing is no longer necessary, are processing, or believe your personal information is inaccurate; (vi) the right to data portability of personal information concerning you that you provided us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format, under certain conditions; (vii) the right object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you, under certain conditions; (viii) the right to lodge a complaint with data protection authorities. If you want to learn more about your rights under the GDPR, you can visit the European Commission’s page on Data Protection.

These rights are provided to all Narro accounts and users.

## Your Consent

By using our site or apps, you consent to our privacy policy.

## Contacting Us

If you have questions regarding this privacy policy, you may email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a6d5d3d6d6c9d4d2e6c8c7d4d4c988c5c9).

## Changes to This Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page and update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

 **This policy was last modified on May 25 th, 2018.**
